# 嗨 大家好
Hi everyone
# 最近我老爸跟伯爷
Recently my dad and my uncle...
# 因为我伯爷在网上看了一个视频“烤全羊”
My uncle watched a video about "whole roasted lamb" on the Internet
# 所以老是念了很久
So he has been longing for it for a while
# 说想要吃烤全羊
Saying that he wants to eat whole roasted lamb
# 然后我本身是做厨师嘛 本身烤全羊也是我的拿手菜
Well, I am a cook and I am good at cooking whole roasted lamb
# 念了这么久就想满足他一个小愿望
Since he has been talking about it for a long time, let me fulfill his wish
# 现在来到我朋友家里面
Now I am at my friend's place
# 看看有没有合适的羊抓一只回去
to buy a lamb suitable for roasting
# 漂不漂亮 你看这个小羊
Isn't it beautiful? Look at this lamb
# 漂亮
It's beautiful
# 这个小羊才刚出世几天还没断奶哦
It was just born several days ago and not weaned yet
# 这个羊就是纯天然的没有喂过什么料（饲料）
These lambs are bred naturally. We never feed them with artificial forage
# 没有喂过什么料（饲料）
No artificial forage?
# 嗯
No
# 这些吃草的时候都是赶到山上放的（吃草）
We herd them onto the hills so that they can eat grass
# 这个是公羊还是母羊哦
Is this a ram or a ewe? # ewe前面竟然应该加a，很神奇
# 都是公羊
They are all rams
# 那边才是母羊
The ewes are over there
# 没有角的就是母羊吗
So the ones without horns are ewes?
# （这里）都是
All of these are (ewes)
# 哦 只是还没有长出来
Ok. The horns haven't grown out yet
# 嗯 有些是没有角的
Yep. Some of them do not have horns actually
# 它不让我摸
It doesn't allow me to touch
# 摸一下
Touch it
# 摸到啦
I touched it!
# 摸到了 乖吧
You did? It is so gentle, right?
# 乖
Yes
# 喜欢吗
Do you like it?
# 但是我想摸那个小羊
But I want to touch that lamb
# 小羊啊
That lamb?
# 来嘛 我给你抱一个
Come on. Let me catch one for you
# 来 抱着
Come on. Hug it
# 摸一下就可以了
Just touching it would be fine
# 你抱得稳吗
Can you hold it?
# 好吧
Okay
# 咦 好可爱
Wow it's so cute
# 好啦 还给婆婆
Okay. Give it back to her
# 你帮我抓一个50以下40斤以上的嘛
Please catch a lamb between 40 and 50 jin (20~25 kg) for me
# 妈妈我抱了小羊
Mom! I just hugged a lamb!
# 来 去妈妈那里
Go to your mom's
# 爸爸要准备抓羊
Daddy's gonna catch a lamb
# 来啦来啦来啦
They are coming
# 他来啦
It's coming! #这里感觉不知道是谁来了哈哈哈哈 他lei了
# 扔地上它踩过的不会吃
They don't eat things that have been stepped on
# 那它还多讲究哦
Well they are pretty picky then #请检查这里的picky
# 它踩过的不得吃我都是放到槽槽里喂的
Because of that, I always feed them with the hayrack
# 刚才我喂了一下那个羊
I just fed the lambs
# 就是这样子它会过来吃
They will come to eat if you hold it like this
# 扔到它圈里面它踩过了就不吃
If you throw it into the sheepfold and they step on it, they don't eat it anymore
# 看来这个山羊还是挺讲究的
It seems that they are somewhat picky
# 你站稳了 它会拖着你跑哦
Stand firm. Or it will drag you away
# 站稳一点 听到没有
Stand firm. Did you hear me?
# 你看那个羊在吃奶 沺沺
Look! That lamb is being fed.
# 两个都在吃奶
Both of them are being fed
# 哪里呀
Where?
# 那个羊啊
That lamb over there
# 要得 就是那个嘛
Ok. That one is just fine
# 害怕你还要飞出去 你飞得动不嘛
I know you are afraid. Can you fly away? #请检查这一句
# 先把后脚套上
Put the hind legs in the bag first
# 小心哦
Be careful
# 哦哟 这个才49斤
Oh. This one is just 49 Jin (24.5 kg)
# 49斤要得 就是它
49 Jin? Ok. That's it
# 49斤就49斤
49 Jin is just fine
# 没得好远得你找一根绳子给我迁着回去嘛
I don't live far from here. Just give me a rope and I will leash it back
# 好
Ok
# 走吧
Let's go
# 拜拜
Bye-bye
# 婆婆拜拜
Say bye-bye to your "Popo" #请检查这里的婆婆到底是哪个辈分
# 四伯爷
Uncle!
# 羊来咯
The lamb is right here
# 你在那里牵只的羊哦
Where did you get it?
# 买的吗
You just bought it?
# 嗯 买的
Yeah I bought it
# 长得出一个大羊来
It's supposed to grow into a big goat
# 这只都差不多50斤了
This one is almost 50 Jin (25 kg)
# 长大了100多斤
When it grows up, it will weigh more than 100 Jin
# 就这样
Just like this
# 过几天我有时间了再下来弄
I will come back for it when I am free several days later
# 烤给你吃
I'll roast it for you
# 要得嘛 要得 要得
That's awesome
# 到时候叫二娃牵出去（放羊）
We can ask Er Wa to feed it outside
# 牵出去放一下
Yeah. Herd it somewhere
# 这个羊吃的时候
When we cook the lamb
# 内脏跟头拿来炖
We can make a soup with the head and internal organs
# 然后就在坝子里拿砖来砌一个灶来烤
Then we can build an oven in the "Ba zi" with bricks for roasting # 坝子不知道是什么
# 做烤全羊
So that we can cook roast lamb
# 可以啊
Sounds good
# 二娃
Er Wa!
# 诶 来咯
I am coming!
# 这个羊牵回来了还是去割点草回来喂它哦
Could you cut some grass to feed this lamb?
# 要得嘛 我去割草
Ok. I am going
# 要得
Ok
# 背篼在那里镰刀再屋里去拿出来去割嘛
The basket is over there. The sickle is in the room. You can take them and go
# 割来喂它
Cut some grass to feed it